<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>r. wayne campbell on Wildlife Afield Index</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/r.-wayne-campbell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in r. wayne campbell on Wildlife Afield Index</description>
    <image>
      <title>Wildlife Afield Index</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:25:46 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/r.-wayne-campbell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unsuccessful Introduction of the California Quail to the Queen Charlotte Islands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/unsuccessfulintroductionofcaliforniaquail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:25:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/unsuccessfulintroductionofcaliforniaquail/</guid>
      <description>R. Wayne Campbell
While extracting records from historical correspondance and field diaries and transferring them to the Wildlife Data Centre electronic databases, I came across some unpublished information on an attempt to introduce California Quail (Callipepla californica) (Figure 1) to the Queen Charlotte Islands.
In March 1924, eight pairs of California Quail were transported from Victoria, where the species was successfully introduced in the early 1860s (Carl and Guiguet 1972), and released by Ken Davies at Sandspit on northeastern Moresby Island, Queen Charlotte Islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upland Sandpiper Breeding near Chetwynd, British Columbia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/uplandsandpiperbreeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:25:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/uplandsandpiperbreeding/</guid>
      <description>R. Wayne Campbell
The Upland Sandpiper (Bartramia longicauda) has always been a challenging species to find in British Columbia. At the time of Munro and Cowan (1947) it was known from only nine localities, all but one from the interior of the province. Over the next 43 years the number of localities increased to 47 with many showing up along the coast including Vancouver Island and the Queen Charlotte Islands (Campbell et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Occurence of Wandering Salamander on the Sunshine Coast of British Columbia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/firstoccurenceofwanderingsalamander/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 13:55:24 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/firstoccurenceofwanderingsalamander/</guid>
      <description>Glenn R. Ryder and R. Wayne Campbell
The wandering salamander (Aneides vagrans) (Figure 1), formerly known as the clouded salamander (A. ferreus), occurs at low elevations on Vancouver Island and some adjacent offshore islands. Although it occurs in Oregon, there are no records from mainland Washington and only a few scattered historical records for the extreme southwest mainland coast of British Columbia. (Green and Campbell 1984; Corkran and Thoms 1996). The status of this species outside Vancouver Island is not well known.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
