<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>michael i. preston on Wildlife Afield Index</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/michael-i.-preston/</link>
    <description>Recent content in michael i. preston on Wildlife Afield Index</description>
    <image>
      <title>Wildlife Afield Index</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:26:45 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/michael-i.-preston/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>British Columbia Round-Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/britishcolumbiaroundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:26:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/britishcolumbiaroundup/</guid>
      <description>Field Notes and Caring People
Wildlife dramas and unusual behaviours that are witnessed in the field are unique and of interest to others. It is a privilege to see such events and it is important to document what has been observed. The information is stored in our databases and over time contributes to the natural history and understanding of animals in the province. On occasion, animals also need our help, either directly or passively, through conservation or aid efforts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report of the Wildlife Data Centre - 1 June to 30 June 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/wildlifedatacentrereportjune2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:26:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/wildlifedatacentrereportjune2008/</guid>
      <description>Michael I. Preston
Manager’s Message
It’s interesting how ideas develop and evolve, and when I think about the Wildlife Data Centre and what has been accomplished so far, I’m reminded of a monumental event that took place 35 years ago. On 20 July 1969 Neil Armstrong was the first man to set foot on the moon. Did he do it alone? No. Did it go just as planned? No. Did the success pay off?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Occurence of the Rock Wren on Vancouver Island and Other Islands in the Strait of Georgia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/occurenceoftherockwren/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:25:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/occurenceoftherockwren/</guid>
      <description>Michael I. Preston
The Rock Wren (Salpinctes obsoletus) is widely distributed throughout Mexico, the southern United States from central Texas west to California, and north to southeastern Sakatchewan and west to southwestern British Columbia. In British Columbia it is rare to uncommon in the Rocky Mountain trench, the Fraser River Valley, southern Vancouver Island, and the central interior. In the southern interior, from the US border north to Kamloops, Salmon Arm, and Revelstoke where it is a regular breeder, the Rock Wren is moderately common and local in summer and occasionally in winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Editor - Wildlife Afield - An Introduction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/fromtheeditorpreston/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 21:26:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/fromtheeditorpreston/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to Wildlife Afield, the bi-annual journal of the Biodiversity Centre for Wildlife Studies.
After years of hard work and a few stumbling blocks along the way, I am very excited to announce that the Biodiversity Centre for Wildlife Studies (BCWS), a non-profit society and charitable organization, is now the new and permanent host of British Columbia&amp;rsquo;s Wildlife Data Centre. In the coming years, the BCWS will lead the way in wildlife data storage, archiving, and preservation, while providing a valuable information service to naturalists, land managers, biologists, field researchers, students and teachers, consultants, and the public.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
