<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>birds on Wildlife Afield Index</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/birds/</link>
    <description>Recent content in birds on Wildlife Afield Index</description>
    <image>
      <title>Wildlife Afield Index</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 10:38:08 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/birds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Semipalmated Plover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/wildlife-categories/birds/ploversemipalmated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 10:38:08 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/wildlife-categories/birds/ploversemipalmated/</guid>
      <description>Breeding Nests [1(1): p.14] Eggs [1(1): p.14] Young [1(1): p.14] Lifespan [1(1): p.14] Conservation and Management Human Threats [1(1): p. 14-15] Other Threats [1(1): p. 15] Scientific Collecting [1(1): p. 14-15] Distribution [1(1): p. 11-13] Habitat [1(1): p. 13] Populations [1(1): p. 11-12] </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured Species - Semipalmated Plover</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/featuredspeciessemipalmatedplover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:26:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/featuredspeciessemipalmatedplover/</guid>
      <description>R. Wayne Campbell
The Semipalmated Plover (Charadrius semipalmatus) is a small, common and familiar shorebird identified by a single dark band across its breast. Unlike many of its relatives who feed and fly in large flocks, this tame sandpiper prefers to forage by itself, running a few steps, then darting to snatch some insect, isopod, or worm, before chasing after another morsel. It is a medium- to long-distant migrant and is best seen in spring and autumn where it feeds or rests on open muddy and sandy shores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsuccessful Introduction of the California Quail to the Queen Charlotte Islands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/unsuccessfulintroductionofcaliforniaquail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:25:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/unsuccessfulintroductionofcaliforniaquail/</guid>
      <description>R. Wayne Campbell
While extracting records from historical correspondance and field diaries and transferring them to the Wildlife Data Centre electronic databases, I came across some unpublished information on an attempt to introduce California Quail (Callipepla californica) (Figure 1) to the Queen Charlotte Islands.
In March 1924, eight pairs of California Quail were transported from Victoria, where the species was successfully introduced in the early 1860s (Carl and Guiguet 1972), and released by Ken Davies at Sandspit on northeastern Moresby Island, Queen Charlotte Islands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Occurence of the Rock Wren on Vancouver Island and Other Islands in the Strait of Georgia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/occurenceoftherockwren/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:25:23 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/occurenceoftherockwren/</guid>
      <description>Michael I. Preston
The Rock Wren (Salpinctes obsoletus) is widely distributed throughout Mexico, the southern United States from central Texas west to California, and north to southeastern Sakatchewan and west to southwestern British Columbia. In British Columbia it is rare to uncommon in the Rocky Mountain trench, the Fraser River Valley, southern Vancouver Island, and the central interior. In the southern interior, from the US border north to Kamloops, Salmon Arm, and Revelstoke where it is a regular breeder, the Rock Wren is moderately common and local in summer and occasionally in winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dusky Flycatcher Breeding in the Peace River Region of British Columbia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/duskyflycatcherbreeding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:24:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/duskyflycatcherbreeding/</guid>
      <description>Doug Brown
The Dusky Flycatcher (Empidonax oberholseri) is widely distributed throughout the central interior of British Columbia south of the Bulkley Basin near Smithers and the Fraser-Nechako region near Prince George (Campbell et al. 1997). It is considered a vagrant along the coast and locally rare in the northern interior of the province. Phinney (1998) lists a single record for the Dawson Creek area. There are an additional 10 widely scattered records for the remainder of the northern interior over the past 117 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Habits of the Barn Owl in the Southern Interior of British Columbia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/foodhabitsofthebarnowl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 21:49:32 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/articles/wa1-1/foodhabitsofthebarnowl/</guid>
      <description>Linda M. Van Damme and Mark Nyhof
Abstract
The diet of the Barn Owl (Tyto alba) in the south-central interior of British Columbia was determined from analysis of 1,424 prey remains recovered from 692 pellets collected between 1990 and 1997. Small mammals, principally rodents, were the main prey accounting for 96.4% of all remains. The meadow vole (Microtus pennsylvanicus) was the primary prey accounting for 95.3% of the owl&amp;rsquo;s diet. Secondary prey included birds (3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
